Curriculum Vitae

Name: Joakim Olofsson

E-mail: joakimolovsson@hotmail.com

Mobile nr: 0707350023

Address: Tallparksvägen 10b, lgh 1008

903 54 Umeå

Joakim Olofsson - Creative Engineering Physics



Goal and Professional Profile

I want to combine my mathematical, computer and physics knowledge to solve difficult problems. Preferably in a group where we together as a group solve and develop advanced technology. I'm in search of a job where I will be challenged daily and where I can learn as much as possible.

Problem Solver

After having gone through a lot of mathematics and later applied that math to solve real life problems in physics, I've become a natural problem solver. To solve problems efficiently I believe would benefit your company and stimulate my thirst for solving problems.

Creative Process

A thirst for problem solving has made me take on challenges in the form of creative projects. For example, I'm the project leader of a project to build a particle accelerator at the University. No one involved in the project has direct experience with particle accelerators and it is only through persistent searching we find useful information to find exactly what we need. To not be afraid to think differently and to test alternate approaches are attributes I consider to be of great advantage.

Team Member

To work in a project form, one must know how to work in a group to acchieve results as efficiently as possible. Through working in project form both in courses and in the spare time building accelerators, I have developed this skill.

Handle Stress

Something that has been of a great benefit to me is that the structure of the program Engineering Physics really prepare you to handle stress. We often have 2-3 courses, labs, reports and exams simultaneously, i have combined this with working extra and projects.

As a person Iam responsible, ambitious and initiative taking. I always try to keep moving forward and solve problems, even though they seem impossible.

I have many times in the work as a personal assistent experienced a situation which could be described as an insecure situation but then taken a quick and responsible action.

Name: Joakim Olofsson

E-mail: joakimolovsson@hotmail.com

Mobile nr: 0707350023

Education

2015 - 2020	Engineering Physics, Umeå universitet, 300hp
2015 - 2015	Mathematics and French, Umeå universitet, 30hp
2013 - 2014	Chemistry and Biology, Högskolan i Skövde 30hp
2009 - 2013	Motorman in seafaring, Lindholmens tekniska gymnasium, Göteborg

Work Experience

2016 jun - aug

Personal Assistent, Humana, Göteborgs kommun

also Lerums kommun

During the summer of 2016 I worked with three different organisations to get as much work experience as possible and to learn as much as possible from the situation. This has sharpened my ability to handle several assignments simultaneously and my ability to plan my summer.

2015 -

Personal Assistent, Umeå Kommun, Umeå

To work as a personal assistent is to treat, assist and to medicate people with different types of disabilities.

As no day is like the other when working in the medical field, it has sharpened my abilities in real life problem solving.

2013 - 2015

Elder Care, Lundbygården äldreboende, Gråbo

During two years I worked as a medical aid, where I treated elders and learned a lot about people. I assisted both with physical and mental problems for the elders. The work also teaches me to communicate with people and adapt to new situations.

2012 - 2013

Machine Repair, Stena Line, Göteborg

During my highschool years I did a total of 16 weeks of internship at the company Stena Line. The work involved repair, learning the ships systems and to inspect the ship. I also learned how to work together to watch and to maintain a bigger system.

Certificates

Taking Driver's License spring of 2017 Motorbefäl klass VIII Basic Safety Basic Fire-protection

Languages

Swedish- native language

English- Fluent in both writing and oral

Spanish- Basic knowledge **French-** Basic knowledge

Computer/Engineering Skills

MATLAB - Good knowledge
Programming C - Good knowledge
Programming C++ - Basic knowledge
Comsol Multiphysics - Good knowledge
CAD - Basic knowledge
LaTeX - Good knowledge
Officepackage - Good knowledge

GPA and References are sent when requested